# ALEXANDR POPOV

+79122443612

minelik4@gmail.com \( \rightarrow \) linkedin \( \rightarrow \) telegram

### **SUMMARY**

As a data analyst, for 3 years I have been improving business performance by developing and automating reporting systems, building business processes, as well as providing analytical support and insights in terms of improving metrics and sales.

### EXPERIENCE

## Data Analyst at Mars Wrigley

04.2022 - present

- Saved more than 1000 hours per month of work for the sales department by converting reporting to Power B and optimizing it in Excel using a product management approach in a team of 2 developers
- Increased the efficiency of user interaction with reports and reduced the number of ad hoc tasks by conducting training in the format of webinars and trainings on working with reporting and searching for insights
- Reduced time to discover and fix data from weeks to hours by managing the development of a data validation system through Power BI

## Data Analyst at Mars Food

04.2021 - 04.2022

- Increased annual sales by 400 million rubles in Russia by implementing a project to increase additional points of sale in retail outlets of national customers
- Saved more than 100 hours per month of the work of the Russian sales department by automating reporting using Power Query and optimizing the data model in Power Pivot
- Increased the ROI of promotional activities by 10pp as a result of optimizing the promotional strategy based on data analysis

## Data Analyst at Mars Pet Nutrition

12.2019 - 04.2021

- Increased annual sales by 200 million rubles in Russia by implementing a project to increase the product's presence in X5 retail outlets based on my analysis
- Saved more than 100 hours per month of the work of the sales department of the Ural region by implementing 3 key reports on metrics and sales, having studied Excel and the company's business processes from scratch
- Accelerated the decision-making process of the top management team by developing reports with key metrics and organizing the department performance management process in the review format

### **EDUCATION**

Bachelor's Degree in International Relations at Ural State University (GPA: 4.5/5.0)

2016 - 2020

#### SKILLS

Technical Skills Power BI, DAX, SQL, Dremio, SQL Server, PostgreSQL, Excel, Azure DevOps Other Skills Product Management, Data Visualization, Data Analysis